

# Vincent Duchauffour Machine Learning Engineer

A Paris, France

**\** 06.09.78.66.27

☑ vincent.duchauffour@proton.me

in Linkedin

Github

## **Profile**

My interest in computer science and mathematics has led my career path towards data science. After some experiences that allowed me to focus on business-related, modeling and data engineering tasks, I am nowadays working closely on software engineering aspects of machine learning projects.

This includes maintaining ML librairies for production use, developing and monitoring ML pipelines and improving CI/CD guidelines. I'm really looking towards contributing to open-source software and learning low-level languages (Rust).

### **Skills**

- Python, PyTorch
- Linux, Git, Shell scripts
- Docker, GitHub Actions
- AWS, GCP, DVC, W&B
- SQL, Elasticsearch, MongoDB

## Languages

- French (Native)
- English

## **Experience**

Since Oct. 2022 Machine Learning Engineer - Kinetix

- Maintain our proprietary ML librairies in collaboration with the R&D team, this include:
  - Rewrite large part of the ML codebase with strong OOP principes
     (SOLID principes / Design patterns)
  - Set up the production environment in accordance with DevOps team
     (AWS, code quality, CI/CD, Docker, unit tests, packaging, deployment)
  - Split the ML monolith into multiple independent repositories
- Reduce by 50% the inference time on the main ML pipeline (PyTorch, profilers, model serving optimization)

Sep. 2021 - Sep. 2022 Data Scientist - Yanport

- Design, build and deploy an improvement on existing NLP system with ordinal classification with focus on explainability (NLTK, Spacy, PyTorch, HuggingFace)
- Design, build and deploy new features on the home value estimate engine (CatBoost)
- Maintain and deploy data pipelines and internal scripting

Sep. 2019 - Sep. 2021 Data analyst - Qare

- Design, build and deploy a monitoring tool for data and ETLs quality
- Analytics engineering (DBT)
- Contributing to ETLs and RETLs (MongoDB, AWS Redshift, Salesforce)
- EDA and ad hoc analyses, interact with concerned corporate departments and make public presentation of results
- Build Tableau dashboards

### Education

2021 - 2022

Msc Data Science (IASD) - Paris Dauphine - Apprenticeship at Yanport

Master thesis: Improving an existing NLP system with ordinality, a deep
dive into explainability

2019 - 2021

Msc Digital Humanities - CNAM - Apprenticeship at Qare

Master thesis: Data analysis for efficient telemedecine customer service

Math evening classes - CNAM

Analysis, Linear algebra, Graph theory, Optimization, Probabilities, Statistics

2012-2017

Licence & Master Philosophy - Paris Nanterre